weight lifting belts are arguably the
most helpful accessory that you could
have in your gym bag they assist you
embracing during a heavy lift and in
turn can help you lift heavier while
still keeping proper form there's many
different belts out there for you to
choose from but one of my personal
favorites right now is the quick locking
weightlifting belt from gym Reapers and
so today that's exactly what I'm gonna
be breaking down for y'all
[Music]
what's up my people it's Jake back in
the barbing garage gym with another
review ready to go for y'all this time
I've got the quick locking weight
lifting belt from gym Reapers in this
review I'm going to tell you everything
that you need to know about this belt
from the price and the features of
course some pros and cons and who should
or maybe should not add this to their
gym bag but you know we've reviewed a
lot of weightlifting belts on barbin.com
so if you want to browse our best list
just go and search bar Bend best
weightlifting belts and you can find out
for yourself which ones that we like the
best
foreign
okay so what do I like about this weight
lifting belt well support definitely
matters when you're working out
especially during a heavy lift and I
gotta say I definitely feel supported
when I'm using this belt I really like
how it's made from 100 nylon so it's
going to allow you to be pretty mobile
during explosive movements like a power
clean for example and the pairing of the
velcro strap and the steel roller Buckle
is going to make it a super quick
process to put on or take it off in
between your sets
foreign
okay so there are a few potential cons
you might experience with this belt and
let's talk about support first yes I
definitely feel supported when I'm
working out with this belt but if you
compare you know this nylon build to a
fully leather belt for example
it might not provide the exact same
support that you would receive from that
fully leather belt the velcro strap
definitely feels secure when you're
working out but I understand why some
people would prefer to have a belt with
a lever for example it's also not
tapered in the front which you know
could be a bit of an issue for some
people in terms of Mobility but for the
most part I haven't had any problems
with it
[Music]
okay so in terms of pricing the Jim
Reaper is quick locking weightlifting
bill is listed right around 35 now you
can purchase this directly from the gym
Reaper's website or you can head over to
Amazon and get it that way as well now
compared to the rest of the market this
is a pretty average price there's a
couple companies that charge a little
bit more for a similar style belt but
when you compare you know this belt to a
fully leather belt for example this is a
much cheaper way to go a lot of those
fully leather belts are 120 150 bucks or
so you know 35 dollars that's pretty
solid especially since you can use this
for all of your lifts now it's fully
leather belts less versatile they're
more stiff and they're not really going
to be able to be used for Olympic style
lifts so since you can do pretty much
everything with this belt I think it's a
pretty solid price
okay so let's talk about the build now
and some of the features that you're
going to find with this gym Reapers
quick locking weight lifting belt so
once again this is made from 100 nylon
it's going to allow you to be pretty
mobile during your workouts you know
specifically for those CrossFit and
Olympic style lifts this is really what
this is tailored to now you do have a
steel Buckle right here it's going to be
really durable it's probably going to
last you a lifetime just so long as
everything here holds up I really like
this velcro strap it's going to allow
you to you know get as much pressure as
you want on your core really just as
long as you can continue to pull on it
now you do have a four inch wide profile
right here it's not tapered in the front
Some people prefer a tapered belt but
you know I haven't really seen that too
much in terms of a nylon belt so that's
something you're interested in It's
Gonna most likely have to be a leather
belt now this does come in six different
sizes as well as six different color
options so there's a really good chance
you're going to find one that you know
matches your gym gear and you know all
that good stuff so like I said this is a
really good chance you're gonna find one
that you like now since this does go
around your belly button and not your
hips you know this is how you wear a
weightlifting belt be sure to measure
around your belly button when
determining you know which of the six
sizes are best for you and when you head
over to their website
they're going to break everything down
for you and show you what measurements
you know are going to pair up with what
size
[Music]
yeah
okay so let's go ahead and do a quick
walk around with this weightlifting belt
you know once again this is a fully 100
nylon belt right here there's no padding
on the inside but I think it's pretty
comfortable when you're working out with
it now you do have a steel Buckle right
here and a roller that's going to be you
know how you put the belt on and off
really quickly and once again you know
you do have this velcro strap
and you know just go ahead and throw
this on to show you how to do it it's
really easy like I said just want to go
ahead kind of position everything right
there on your belly button take the
strap
slide it through these two rollers right
here
[Music]
make sure everything's lined up
sometimes it can kind of get slide
around a little bit and basically you
just pull and Pull and pull until you
know you find that exact support that
you're wanting
smack it on there and you're good to go
it's not going to come loose whatsoever
now once again you know it's not tapered
in the front it's got that four inch
wide profile but you know you're still
able to be pretty mobile with this belt
and because of the fact of this velcro
strap you know you can always tighten it
up whenever you need to and just
continue to get that solid support that
you need you know once again this comes
in six different sizes as well as six
different colors so there's a really
good chance you're going to find one
that suits your needs out there whenever
you go to take it off it's just same
process in reverse order just pull that
out I'm gonna grab up right here
it's going to make that slide out and
then you can just guide everything
through and you can take it off super
fast
okay so who should purchase the gym
Reaper's quick locking weight lifting
belt well anybody who's looking for a
highly versatile belt they can use for
their Olympic lifts as well as their
traditional power lifts I think this is
a really good option for you to consider
you know I use it for my power cleans
also use it for my squats I don't think
you can really go wrong with this belt
right here if you're looking for a belt
it's going to allow you to choose the
exact amount of support and pressure
that you want on your core I think
you're really going to enjoy this velcro
strap you know you can make it as tight
as you want just as long as you can
continue to pull on the strap and you
know because of that strap it's also
going to be a very solid option for
anybody who wants a belt they can put on
or take off you know really quickly in
between their sets
[Music]
okay so what about the people who might
not want to purchase this weightlifting
belt well let's talk about the design if
you're in the market for a belt that's
tapered in the front you're going to
want to keep looking that's not the case
with this one right here just remember
that's most likely going to have to be a
leather belt if you're looking for a
belt that has a lever to keep everything
nice and secured you might not be too
crazy about this velcro strap and lastly
you know a lot of people prefer a belt
that does have padding on the inside and
that's not the case here so you'll also
want to keep looking at that's a trait
that you're looking for that's about all
I have for you guys today on the gym
Reapers quick locking weightlifting
build I personally love working out with
this belt I can use it for my explosive
movements like a power clean but it
still provides me with enough support
when I go to do my squats and my
deadlifts I also really enjoy this
velcro strap it's going to allow me to
really choose the exact amount of
pressure and support that I want for my
lifts even though it's not tapered in
the front and there's no padding on the
inside I would still recommend this belt
to a lot of people out there thanks for
watching everybody I hope this video was
really helpful and I was able to answer
every single question that you have
about this weightlifting belt as always
stay posted for my next video but for
now head over to barbin.com and you can
read more about this product just search
bar Bend Jim Reaper's quick locking
weightlifting belt review and you'll
find everything that I talked about here
today I'll see y'all next time
thank you
[Music]
foreign